CHRISTOPHER W. WAGNER

(480) 376-4303 wagne279@purdue.edu azcwagner.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My goal is to use formal methods to create provably-correct and reliable software, protocols, and systems. I am interested in distributed systems, formal methods, programming languages, and information security. My current research focuses on modeling and verifying provably-correct distributed systems.

EDUCATION

Purdue University

PhD Student, Computer Science

August 2018 - Present

GPA: 3.95

Utah State University

Bachelor of Computer Science

December 2016

GPA: 4.0

HONORS AND AWARDS

Professional Activities Grant Student Travel Fellowship

Presidential Scholarship

Presidential Scholars Eagle Scout Rank OOPSLA 2021 (ACM SIGPLAN PAC)

CAV 2019

Utah State University Boy Scouts of America

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-Reviewed Conferences

- · N. Jaber, S. Jacobs, C. Wagner, M. Kulkarni, and R. Samanta. Parameterized Verification of Systems with Global Synchronization and Guards. In Computer Aided Verification (CAV), 2020.
- · N. Jaber, C. Wagner, S. Jacobs, M. Kulkarni, and R. Samanta. QuickSilver: Modeling and Parameterized Verification for Distributed Agreement-Based Systems. In *Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages, and Applications (OOPSLA)*, 2021.
- · Y. Bao, K. Sundararajah, R. Malik, Q. Ye, C. Wagner, N. Jaber, F. Wang, M. Ameri, D. Lu, A. Seto, B. Delaware, R. Samanta, A. Kate, C. Garman, J. Blocki, P. Letourneau, B. Meister, J. Springer, T. Rompf, and M. Kulkarni. HACCLE: Metaprogramming for Secure Multi-Party Computation. In Generative Programming: Concepts & Experiences (GPCE), 2021.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Purdue University - Teaching Assistant

Jan 2020 - Present

- · Assisted with course development in addition to typical TA duties
- · Designed homework problems to assess student proficiency in first-order logic, temporal logic, model checking, and abstract interpretation

Purdue University - Research Assistant

Aug 2018 - Present

- · Working on the Discover[i] project for automated parameterized verification and synthesis of distributed systems
- · Contributed to the Purdue HACCLE project aiming to increase the usability and performance of secure multi-party computation.
- · Led an Abstraction-Guided Program Repair project targeting scalable and sound program repair for real-world programs

- · Expanded the functionality of code contracts in CBMC to enable compositional reasoning in proofs involving functions with side effects. This entailed adding a construct to identify the memory locations which may be modified by a function and enforcing that constraint within the function body. This allowed some function calls to be replaced by their contract pre- and post-conditions surrounding a series of havocking statements, eliminating costly exploration of long call stacks.
- · Proved functional correctness for portions of Amazon's FreeRTOS and s2n projects using CBMC

Northrop Grumman - Associate Software Engineer

Mar 2017 - Jul 2018

- · Engineered RTOS error inducement techniques for PowerPC programs
- · Updated software test scripts and documentation for USGS Landsat 9 satellite
- \cdot Detected and identified root cause of bugs in embedded flight software

Utah State University - Computer Science Tutor

Aug 2014 - Dec 2016

- · Guided CS students in understanding and debugging coding assignments
- · Taught problem-solving and programming fundamentals

Micron Technology - IT Software Engineer Intern

Summer 2016

- · Supported a scrum agile team in stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospectives
- · Established automated build and testing assets using HP UFT and Jenkins

Hewlett Packard (Enterprise) - Software Engineer Intern

Summer 2015

- · Engineered dynamic web apps using ASP.NET Razor
- · Patched internal web framework by processing Bugzilla tickets

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Discover[i]

This project combines modular reasoning with parameterized model checking to push the boundaries of automated parameterized reasoning. Our Guarded Synchronization Protocols (GSP) model enables parameterized verification and forms the theoretical foundation for Quicksilver, our higher-level verification system, which supports high-level primitives for abstracting distributed consensus as an atomic program-level construct. In this project, I designed the initial phase-analysis used to generate guards for transitions in the GSP model. I also initiated the lifting of the GSP model's decidable fragment to the semantics of programs written in Mercury, the modeling language of Quicksilver. This allows us to leverage decidability and cutoff results for parameterized verification in the GSP model by performing static checks on Mercury programs, saving the nontrivial effort of translating these programs into the GSP model.

HACCLE

This IARPA-funded project aimed to make secure multi-party computation (MPC) more powerful and accessible. We combined MPC techniques such as garbled circuits and fully homomorphic encryption with a layered programming architecture, based on lightweight modular staging, to allow programmers with minimal security background to write secure distributed programs. In this project, my work focused on designing the syntax of Harpoon, our surface language. I also formalized a decomposition of secure functions which are invertible modulo an equivalence relation, which can improve performance by reducing the need for expensive cryptographic operations.

Abstraction-Guided Program Repair

The high-level goal of this project was to improve the scalability of fully-automated program repair. I

developed a framework to automatically generate Boolean (abstract) programs from C programs with respect to a set of Boolean predicates with the intention of using the Sketch Synthesis framework to complete undefined expressions in those Boolean programs. By generating abstract programs, and repairing them in their abstract form, we hoped to use details from the abstraction process to inform the construction and concretization of repairs.

SERVICE AND MENTORING

Purdue CSGSA (Computer Science Graduate Student Association)

· Treasurer 2021-2022

PurPL (Purdue PL Group)

· Student Seminar Coordinator, 2018-2019

Reviewing

· Adjunct Reviewer, CAV 2021

Mentoring

- · Mentored a visiting Summer 2019 intern on the Abstraction-Guided Program Repair project by building up student's technical background and supervising tool development.
- · Student panel member, prospective PhD student visit day, 2019

TALKS

PLDI '22: Discover[i]: Taming Unbounded Distributed Systems with Modular, Bounded Reasoning (co-presented tutorial)

PurPL Seminar: Bounded Verification of Doubly-Unbounded Parameterized Systems

PurPL Seminar: Modeling and Verifying (Multi-)Parameterized Systems

PurPL Seminar: Discover/i/ (see Research Projects, above)

PurPL Seminar: SQLizer: Query Synthesis from Natural Language by N. Yaghmazadeh et al. PurPL Seminar: Modular and Verified Automatic Program Repair by F. Logozzo and T. Ball

FOR RECRUITERS

Languages

Java, C, C++, C#, Python, Perl, PHP, MySQL, PostGreSQL, PowerPC Assembly Coq, Scheme, PostScript, Prolog

Tools

CBMC, Z3, CPAchecker, Sketch, ANTLR, GNU Bison/Yacc Git, Subversion, Bugzilla, Jenkins, HP Unified Functional Testing (UFT) Amazon EC2, Wind River Simics

Work Authorization

U.S. Citizenship